# Ada F. Lovelace

lovelace.af@gmail.com | 647-573-3735 | Toronto, ON

**LinkedIn:** <u>linkedin.com/in/aflovelace</u> | **GitHub:** <u>github.com/flovelace</u> | **Portfolio:** <u>https://developer-portfolio-ruby-three.vercel.app/</u>

Full stack software engineer leveraging a wealth of product liaison experience in several startup environments. Dedicated to building and optimising web pages, mobile apps, and software with a distinct focus on delighting the user with the best experience possible. A dedicated solution seeker with an adaptable approach to learning new frameworks and technologies.

#### **Technical Skills**

Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, JavaScript, Bootstrap, REST API, React, NextJS, graphQL, JINJA, Hubble

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Sequelize, Mongoose, Python, Flask

**Mobile:** Flutter

Tools: Atlassian JIRA & Confluence, Git, Agile, SCRUM, Heroku, Docker, Vercel, Postico

# **Relevant Work Experience**

Drop Mobility May 2022 - Present

Full Stack Software Engineer

Toronto, ON

- Designing and building responsive web pages according to client specification using TypeScript, React, and NextJS.
- Implementing features, quality of life updates, and bug fixes from the product roadmap to the mobile application using Flutter.
- Performing coding solutions and building with product scale-ability in mind.
- Participating in engineering standup to discuss daily progress, potential solutions to issues, and product ideas and direction.
- Adhering to company coding standards to write clean and understandable code, and participating in coding reviews.
- Participating in peer coding sessions to learn and gain further understanding into the tasks of other engineer team members.

Naborly
July 2019 - Feb 2022
Product Liaison
Toronto, ON

- Reading and understanding the company codebase and development environment (AWS).
- Tracking, replicating, resolving, and reporting bug/user experience issues via Atlassian JIRA.
- Assessing the priority of bugs and product enhancements, and proposing potential coding solutions to the engineering team.
- Creating Looker queries with SQL for data analysis to create actionable customer journeys (loyalty, retention, stickiness) for product development and creation.
- Coding automated and single-send API email campaigns on Hubspot (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and NodeJS).
- Webmaster for Zendesk integrated support page, Hubspot marketing website, and Hubspot blog. (HTML5, JavaScript, JINJA, HUBBLE, and CSS3).

Fleet Complete
Aug 2017 - May 2019
Technical Support Analyst 2
Toronto, ON

- Troubleshooting, re-programming, and re-calibrating GPS units (remotely).
- Training and assisting clients with a variety of software usage and hardware maintenance, and reporting issues and bugs via Microsoft Dynamics and Zendesk.
- Handling escalations from internal departments and junior agents to provide timely resolutions.
- Proactively analysing user data reports to identify and determine trends in problematic hardware.

### **Projects**

#### Cool Tech Blog | Repo | Deployed

Lead developer

- A tech related blog where users can post tech news, tech thoughts and tech opinions!
- Uses SQL (Sequelize) to store all user information, and uses bcrypt for secure login.
- JavaScript, SQL, Sequelize, NodeJS, ExpressJS, HTML5, Bootstrap, and CSS3.

## Pizza Hunt | Repo | Deployed

Lead developer

- A social media site where users can post their favourite pizza creations, and receive comments!
- Uses MongoDB to store all user information, and bcrypt for secure user login and account creation.
- JavaScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, NodeJS, ExpressJS, HTML5, and CSS3.

### Taskmaster Pro | Repo | Deployed

Lead developer

**Grad:** Feb 2022

- A kanban style board for organising tasks (like JIRA, Asana or Monday.)
- User's tasks persist in the local storage.
- JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, and CSS3.

#### **Education**

University of Toronto: School of Continuing Studies, Toronto

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

University of Stirling, Stirling, Scotland Grad: Sept 2010

MLitt in the Gothic Imagination with Merit

University of Stirling, Scotland Grad: May 2009

Bachelor of Arts in English Studies